[
    {
        "question": "Who invented C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) Dennis Ritchie",
            "b) Ken Thompson",
            "c) Brian Kernighan",
            "d) Bjarne Stroustrup"
        ],
        "answer": "d) Bjarne Stroustrup"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) C++ is an object oriented programming language",
            "b) C++ is a procedural programming language",
            "c) C++ supports both procedural and object oriented programming language",
            "d) C++ is a functional programming language"
        ],
        "answer": "c) C++ supports both procedural and object oriented programming language"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax of including a user defined header file in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) #include [userdefined]",
            "b) #include “userdefined”",
            "c) #include <userdefined.h>",
            "d) #include <userdefined>"
        ],
        "answer": "b) #include “userdefined”"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used for comments in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) /* comment */",
            "b) // comment */",
            "c) // comment",
            "d) both // comment or /* comment */"
        ],
        "answer": "d) both // comment or /* comment */"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following extension is used for user-defined header file in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) hg",
            "b) cpp",
            "c) h",
            "d) hf"
        ],
        "answer": "c) h"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct identifier in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) VAR_1234",
            "b) $var_name",
            "c) 7VARNAME",
            "d) 7var_name"
        ],
        "answer": "a) VAR_1234"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of Constructor in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) Default constructor",
            "b) Parameterized constructor",
            "c) Copy constructor",
            "d) Friend constructor"
        ],
        "answer": "d) Friend constructor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following approach is used by C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) Left-right",
            "b) Right-left",
            "c) Bottom-up",
            "d) Top-down"
        ],
        "answer": "c) Bottom-up"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is virtual inheritance in C++?",
        "options": [
            "a) C++ technique to enhance multiple inheritance",
            "b) C++ technique to ensure that a private member of the base class can be accessed somehow",
            "c) C++ technique to avoid multiple inheritances of classes",
            "d) C++ technique to avoid multiple copies of the base class into children/derived class"
        ],
        "answer": "d) C++ technique to avoid multiple copies of the base class into children/derived class"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if the following C++ statement is compiled and executed?\nint *ptr = NULL;\ndelete ptr",
        "options": [
            "a) The program is not semantically correct",
            "b) The program is compiled and executed successfully",
            "c) The program gives a compile-time error",
            "d) The program compiled successfully but throws an error during run-time"
        ],
        "answer": "b) The program is compiled and executed successfully"
    }
]